[
  {
    "question": "The precursor for the synthesis of aromatic amino acids is",
    "options": [
      "phosphoenolpyruvate",
      "pyruvate",
      "oxaloacetate",
      "Alpha-ketoglutarate"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The plant hormone indole-3-acetic acid is derived from",
    "options": [
      "Histidine",
      "Tyrosine",
      "Tryptophan",
      "Proline"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following small molecules is a prerequisite for fatty acid oxidation?",
    "options": [
      "Inositol",
      "Choline",
      "Carnitine",
      "Glycerol"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following proteases does NOT cleave on the carboxyl side of any Arginine residue in a protein?",
    "options": [
      "Trypsin",
      "Proteinase K",
      "Thrombin",
      "Chymotrypsin Correct Answer = d"
    ],
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The enzyme amylase can break alpha glycosidic linkage between glucose monomers. Hence, amylase can digest which one of the following carbohydrate?",
    "options": [
      "Cellulose",
      "Starch",
      "Chitin",
      "Xylan"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Oxidation of one molecule of glucose via the glycerol-phosphate shuttle produces",
    "options": [
      "32 molecules of ATP",
      "32 molecules of NADPH",
      "30 molecules of ATP",
      "30 molecules of NADPH"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one the following reaction mechanisms drives the conversion of low energy 3-phosphoglyceraldehyde to high energy 1,3-bisphosphoglycerate?",
    "options": [
      "Oxidation without anhydride bond formation",
      "Oxidation coupled with anhydride bond formation",
      "Substrate level phosphorylation",
      "Formation of carboxylate"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The reactions leading to the formation of amino acids from the TCA cycle intermediates are?",
    "options": [
      "carboxylation",
      "isomerization",
      "transamination",
      "decarboxylation"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following metabolic processes in mammalian cells does NOT occur in the mitochondria?",
    "options": [
      "Citric acid cycle",
      "Oxidative phosphorylation",
      "Fatty acid B-oxidation",
      "Glycolysis"
    ],
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Nitrogenase reduces N2 to NH3. Metal co-factors required for this activity are",
    "options": [
      "Fe & Cu",
      "Mo & Fe",
      "Mo & Mn",
      "Cu & Mn"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  }
]